# 哈喽大家好
Hey guys,
# 我伯爷今天肉没有卖完
My uncle had some meat left unsold today at his butcher stall.
# 然后用他的猪肉去换了泥鳅
So he traded it for some pond loaches.
# 换了1斤泥鳅
I got 1 jin (0.5kg) of pond loaches.
# 拿1斤肉换1斤泥鳅
1 jin (0.5kg) of pork for 1 jin pond loaches.
# 我没吃亏
I am happy with that.
# 上次用猪脚换甲鱼我吃了点亏
Last time trading pork trotters with soft-shelled turtles was not a great deal.
# 这次我换的就过称两头价
But this time, they are even in price.
# 这个泥鳅我伯爷从来没有吃过泥鳅汤
My uncle has never tried pond loach soup before.
# 所以今天准备1块豆腐
We need a chunk of tofu.
# 这块豆腐是人家送我的
A friend gave this tofu to me.
# 煮一个汤
We will use this to make our soup.
# 好我们现在来处理这个泥鳅
Now let's process this loach.
# 把泥鳅给它抓出来
We need to take it out.
# 轻轻的放下去
Lay it down gently.
# 然后稍微按它一下
And slightly press it.
# 把它的头剁掉
Chop off its head.
# 剁掉了头之后它就不会动了
Now it's not moving anymore.
# 然后我们用刀压住它的尾巴
Then, we press on its tail with our knife.
# 这样子用刀压住它的尾巴
Like this.
# 这样子给它往前面挤
and push forward.
# 挤压
Push and squeeze.
# 通过挤压它里面的肠子和胆就会掉出来
We will be able to squeeze out the guts.
# 这样子就可以啦
Like this.
# 这样子就是它的内脏
Those are its guts.
# 好 我们来看一下第二条
Now let's move on to the next one.
# 再杀一条看一下
Let's do it one more time.
# 把它的头剁掉
Chop off the head,
# 然后用刀压住它的尾巴
push on the tail,
# 就可以啦
and it's done.
# 挤出来的蛋的话就不要吧
What about the eggs that just came out.
# 要不要这个蛋
Do we keep them?
# 不要 没有多少点
No, since there's not much.
# 一点点不要了
Just a tiny bit. Throw it away
# 好 我们来看一下第三条
Now, let's move on to the third one.
# 首先不要动它
Don't touch it initially.
# 让它安静下来
Just wait for it to rest.
# 然后切掉它的头
And then chop off its head.
# 它好像有一点不安
It seems a little agitated.
# 还有点顽固这条泥鳅
It's stubborn.
# 切掉它的头
Chop off its head.
# 然后这边用菜刀压住它的尾巴
Press on its tail with the knife.
# 这样子往前面挤
And squeeze forward.
# 可以啦
Done!
# 然后没有挤出来的我们再压住这里
If there are still guts remaining, we can squeeze it again.
# 这样一拉就掉了
And pull it.
# 我觉得这个籽还是要到
I feel like we can keep those eggs.
# 不要 你这点不好吃
Nah, not much you can do with this little
# 要到嘛万一多呢
Let's keep them. What if there are a lot?
# 要得也可以啊
Fine fine.
# 好啦 我们这个泥鳅就处理好啦
So we are done processing the pond loaches.
# 本来说不要这个蛋的结果每一条好像都有蛋
I didn't want to keep the eggs but it seems there are eggs in every loach.
# 然后我就把它留起来了
So I collected them.
# 现在来准备一些辅料
Now let's prepare some other ingredient.
# 先切一块姜
First, slice a chunk of ginger.
# 然后我们再准备几根小葱
And some green onions.
# 把它挽起来就可以了
Just tie a knot like this.
# 到时候汤煮好了之后就把这个葱捞出来就行了
We will take it out after the soup is done.
# 然后我们来把这块豆腐切了
Now, let's slice the tofu.
# 好大哦这块豆腐
This tofu is huge.
# 估计有1斤多
It's about 1 jin (0.5kg).
# 肯定是1斤多
For sure.
# 切成厚片就可以
We can just slice the tofu into thick slices.
# 切好大一块的哦
That's big.
# 煮汤的要久煮一会儿
The soup needs to be cooked for a while.
# 要的啊 这样吃起爽口点
So it will taste better.
# 我们这个豆腐还是选老豆腐好一点
As for the tofu, we'd better use firm tofu.
# 老豆腐更香
It has a richer taste.
# 好 现在可以了
Ok, we are done.
# 帮我拿下葱嘛 可以煮了
Can you hand me the green onion? We can start cooking.
# 可以开工了
Let's do it.
# 我们一般煮这个鱼汤先准备开水
Typically, we prepare boiling water before making the fish soup.
# 煮鱼汤就成功一半了
With boiling water, we are halfway to success.
# 可以了四伯爷
Uncle, it's good.
# 诶呀 这个汤好白哦
This soup is so white.
# 加不加鸡精呢
Do we need chicken bouillon powder?
# 不加鸡精
No.
# 最后再撒一点葱花
Now let's sprinkle some chopped green onion on the top.
# 好
Done!
# 来了 汤来了
Here comes the soup.
# 这汤看这个颜色估计喝起安逸哦
I can tell this soup is going to be tasty just from its color.
# 我们这个汤是黄的
It's slightly golden in color
# 是为什么呢 是因为这个汤里面有泥鳅的蛋
Why? Because we added the eggs.
# 下锅煎了就变黄了
After searing the eggs turned golden
# 如果是平时的话我们这个汤应该是白的
It would have been white without the eggs.
# 所以这个也不影响
But it's not a big deal.
# 品尝哈这个汤看
Try it.
# 烫哦 小心
Oh, it's hot. Be careful.
# 刚刚煮出来的
Freshly out of the pot.
# 舌头给你烫个泡
It will burn your tongue
# 好喝
Delicious.
# 就是太烫了
It's just too hot.
# 嗯 可以
Em, that's good.
# 这个汤的话稍微淡一点点
The taste is on the lighter side.
# 如果大家比较介意的话可以放咸一点
If you want, you can add more salt.
# 鲜撒
Does it taste good?
# 吃起不晓得好安逸
Nice!
# 伯爷（汤）鲜不鲜
Uncle, isn't it tasty?
# 鲜 我就是说下面拿这个汤冒起才安逸
Yea, it will be even better to serve this soup with some noodles.
# 我们四川人只要是好喝的汤都可以拿来下面条
In Sichuan, we love noodle soup.
# 鲜就可以了
As long as the soup is tasty
# 还有我们这个泥鳅豆腐汤特别适合一些体质比较虚弱的人喝
This soup is also good for people with weaker health.
# 这个特别的好
So good.
# 这个汤的营养价值非常高
This soup is highly nutritious.
# 如果是做泥鳅豆腐汤的话我不建议大家用盐去把泥鳅腌死
I don't suggest using salt to kill the loach,
# 或者是用开水烫死
nor using boiling water.
# 就直接是这样下去把它那层粘液煎香
Just put it in like this and sear until aromatic.
# 煎香了之后再放开水下去煮
Then add boiling water.
# 好烫哦
It's so hot.
# 你喝那么快咋子嘛
Why are you eating so fast?
# 太烫了
It's really hot.
# 你好慌啊
You are in such a rush.
# 我去端饭过来
I will go get a bowl of rice.
# 哎呀 喝起安逸
Oh, so good.
# 烫得很 我都整出汗水了
It's hot. I'm even sweating.
# 你还是慢慢喝嘛不要急嘛
Slow it down man.
# 你看到我喝那么快你还是跟着喝那么快
You are eating so fast because you see me eating fast.
# 还有这里
There are more here.
# 晓得还有半瓷盆
I know. There is still like half a bowl left.